(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
THE IDOLM@STER
283プロダクション ストレイライト 黛冬優子 (宣伝隊長)
283 Production Straylight, Fuyuko Mayuzumi (Promotional Captain)
ラブライブ！ School idol project series
Love Live! School idol project series
Aqours 津島善子 (宣伝隊長)
Aqours, Yoshiko Tsushima (Promotional Captain)
hololive
ホロライブ ラプラス・ダークネス (「アイドルマスター」アンバサダー)
Hololive, La+ Darknesss ("The Idolmaster" Ambassador)
にじさんじ
Nijisanji
にじさんじ ドーラ (「ラブライブ！」アンバサダー)
Nijisanji, Dora ("Love Live!" Ambassador)
MUSIC BIGBANG!
皆さん、こんばんは！
Good evening, everyone!
ストレイライトの黛冬優子でーす！
I'm Fuyuko Mayuzumi from Straylight!
みんな、ふゆって呼んでね！
Everyone, please call me Fuyu!
リトルデーモンたち、ごきげんよう。
Greetings, my Little Demons.
私はヨハネ。
I am Yohane.
美しさのあまり天界を追放された堕天使。
The fallen angel who was banished from the heavens for her excessive beauty.
ということで、この番組は明日から
And so, this is a music program commemorating the event
東京ドームで開催されるイベントを記念した音楽番組です！
held at Tokyo Dome starting tomorrow!
一緒に宣伝隊長を務める津島善子ちゃんと共にお送りします！
I'll be hosting together with Yoshiko Tsushima-chan, who is serving as a promotional captain with me!
善子じゃなくて、ヨハネね！
It's not Yoshiko, it's Yohane!
それに冬優子、
Also, Fuyuko,
今日は私たち二人だけじゃなくて、超強力な助っ人が来てるのよね！
today we're not alone; some super-powerful helpers are here!
はい！今日は冬優子たちと一緒に
Yes! Today, we've invited some wonderful ambassadors
この番組を盛り上げてくれる素敵なアンバサダーをゲストにお呼びしています！
as guests to help us liven up the show!
刮目せよ！
Feast your eyes!
我輩のお名前はラプラス・ダークネスだ！
My name is La+ Darknesss!
今日は冬優子を応援しに来たぞ！
I've come to cheer for Fuyuko today!
よー、人間ども！
Yo, humans!
ラブライブ！アンバサダー、ドーラじゃよー！
I'm the Love Live! ambassador, Dora!
ヨハネを応援しに来ました！
I've come to cheer for Yohane!
というわけで、冬優子と私の助っ人としてそれぞれ来てもらったわ。
And so, they've come as helpers for Fuyuko and me, respectively.
ドーラ、あなたはファイヤードレイクだそうね。
Dora, I hear you're a fire drake.
このヨハネの眷属として存分に暴れてもらうわよ。
As Yohane's familiar, I expect you to run wild to your heart's content.
本物の善子ちゃん！かわいい！
The real Yoshiko-chan! So cute!
やばいやばい！
Oh man, oh man!
ヨハネ！
Yohane!
ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry.
でも、今日はヨハネと共演できて本当に光栄です！
But I'm truly honored to perform with Yohane today!
ヨハネの眷属として、ファイヤードレイクのドーラ、
As Yohane's familiar, the fire drake Dora,
馳せ参じました！
has arrived!
今日はよろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to working with you today!
冬優子たちのアンバサダーはラプラスちゃんです！
Fuyuko's ambassador is La+-chan!
とってもかわいい〜！
She's so cute~!
ラプラスちゃん、よろしくね！
La+-chan, nice to meet you!
ラブ様だよ！
It's Lap-sama!
今回のコラボで、冬優子のこともっと好きになっちゃったぞ！
I've come to like Fuyuko even more through this collaboration!
貴様らもこんなコラボ滅多に見ることができないから、ありがたく思えよ！
You lot better be grateful, 'cause you won't see a collaboration like this very often!
メンバー紹介も終わったところで、今回は歌合戦にちなんで、
Now that the introductions are over, since this is a singing competition,
メンバーが分かれているんだけど、
the members are split up,
せっかくだし、今日だけのチーム名をつけてみない？
but since we're here, why don't we come up with team names just for today?
おっ、いいですね！
Oh, that sounds good!
歌合戦番組っぽくなってきたぞ！
It's starting to feel like a singing competition show!
うーん、チーム名、何がいいかな？
Hmm, a team name... What would be good?
ドレイクたち、結構名前の一部をくっつけて
Drakes often decide on team names by
チーム名を決めることが多いんですけど、
joining parts of their names together,
善子ちゃん、善子×ドーラだから...
Yoshiko-chan, since it's Yoshiko x Dora...
ヨシーラとか？
How about "Yoshira"?
ヨハネ！
Yohane!
それにめちゃくちゃダサい！
And that's incredibly tacky!
いや、ダサいな...
Yeah, it is tacky...
ふゆ、とってもかわいいと思うな。
Fuyu thinks it's very cute.
絶対ダメよ！
Absolutely not!
それじゃあ、私が直々に決めてあげる。
In that case, I shall decide it myself.
リトルデーモンたちもよく聞きなさい。
Listen well, my Little Demons.
そうね... ヨハドラよ！
Let's see... It's "Yohadora"!
少しだけ、変わったかな？
Did it change... just a little bit?
結構いいと思ったんだけどな...
I thought it was pretty good, though...
いいえ、私ヨハネの発言は絶対なんだから！
No, my word as Yohane is absolute!
もうこれに決まりよ！ドーラ、いいわよね？
It's already decided! Dora, that's fine with you, right?
はい、ヨハネがそういうなら大丈夫です！
Yes, if Yohane says so, it's fine!
よろしい。
Excellent.
それでそちらはどうするの？
And what about you guys?
うーん、
Hmm,
二人の名前の最初の2文字をとって、
taking the first two characters of our names,
「ふゆラプ」なんてどうかな？
how about "Fuyurapu"?
まぁ、そのまま過ぎるけど、冬優子がいいならいいか。
Well, it's a bit direct, but if Fuyuko likes it, I guess it's fine.
嬉しい！ありがとう！
I'm so happy! Thank you!
それじゃ名前も決まったところで、
Well then, now that the name has been decided,
番組を始めていくわよ。
let's start the program.
全国のリトルデーモンたち！
Little Demons across the country!
私たちの音楽に酔いしれなさい！
Indulge yourselves in our music!
THE IDOLM@STER
hololive
先攻 チーム ふゆラブ
First Turn: Team Fuyu Rabu
注目せよ！
Pay attention!
Can you feel "Madness" この世界の全て
Can you feel "Madness"? Everything in this world...
合縁事変 歌：黛 冬優子
Aien Jihen, Sung by: Fuyuko Mayuzumi
冬優子がラプラスの曲を異次元カバー
Fuyuko covering La+'s song across dimensions
Can you feel "Galaxy" 果てを飛び超えた Glory
Can you feel "Galaxy"? Glory that soared past the horizon.
バイアスかかるバイブスで 深淵より宿すパワーを tune up
With biased vibes, tune up the power dwelling from the abyss.
Massで成り立つCapitalに 一罰百戒 穿つ「理想像」
In a Capital built on the masses, pierce an "ideal" as a warning to all.
傷天害理 汝、二乗で満たす存在意義
Inhumanity, thou shall fulfill your raison d'être by squaring it.
In the Flow 直な「ない」返し「はい」 獅子博兎 +Impact!
In the flow, a blunt "no" returned with "yes." Full strength on a trivial task + Impact!
まわりまわる多様性を 感情的なルールで縛り付け
Binding the spinning diversity with emotional rules,
「うるせぇ全く！」
"Shut up, seriously!"
うねりうねる可能性で
With twisting and turning possibilities,
全て超えた Identity
Identity that has surpassed everything.
Can you feel my soul
Baby, up & up now 3, 2, 1
Nothing bad happened.
案じたってまわる循環定義
Even if you worry, it's just a spinning circular definition.
変わらぬ真理 合縁奇縁の淀み点
Unchanging truth, the stagnation point of strange twists of fate.
make it Nothing bad happened.
君は君 いらぬ疑心暗鬼
You are you, no need for groundless suspicion.
不毛なBlowと焦らすFlow
Fruitless Blow and impatient Flow,
募る鼓動でHigh up & up
getting high up & up with gathering heartbeats.
我が道をゆくMinority あざとくIrony
A minority walking their own path, cunning irony.
ちらり見せるピュアなハート 悩殺御免
Glimpsing a pure heart, sorry for being so captivating.
夢描いていた名声赫赫 人類学 核にtuning up
The illustrious fame dreamed of, tuning up at the core of anthropology.
すべて解き明かす 心満たす様
Unraveling everything, satisfying the heart.
その美的な知識を刺激して
Stimulating that aesthetic knowledge,
私的に生きてる体も shaking up and shape up
even the body living privately is shaking up and shaping up.
我が道をゆく共犯者
An accomplice walking their own path.
Are you ready to fall into deep.
かすむ視界は冥冥 ひびく名声
The hazy vision is pitch dark, echoing fame.
叫べ「メーデー」
Cry out "Mayday!"
無垢な犠牲 足りない愛を狂わす
Innocent sacrifice, driving insufficient love mad.
まわりまわる多様性を 感情的なルールで縛り付け
Binding the spinning diversity with emotional rules,
「うるせぇ全く！」
"Shut up, seriously!"
うねりうねる可能性で
With twisting and turning possibilities,
全て超えた Identity
Identity that has surpassed everything.
Can you feel my soul
Baby, up & up now 3, 2, 1
Nothing bad happened.
案じたってまわる循環定義
Even if you worry, it's just a spinning circular definition.
変わらぬ真理 合縁奇縁の淀み点
Unchanging truth, the stagnation point of strange twists of fate.
make it Nothing bad happened.
君は君 いらぬ疑心暗鬼
You are you, no need for groundless suspicion.
不毛なBlowと焦らすFlow
Fruitless Blow and impatient Flow,
募る鼓動でHigh up & up
getting high up & up with gathering heartbeats.
異次元フェス開催記念 MUSIC BIGBANG!
Ijigen Fes Commemoration Music Program MUSIC BIGBANG!
キミにFall in love 恋のSOS ずっと胸が苦しいんです
Fall in love with you, SOS of love. My chest has been aching for so long.
ハヤケRescue 「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Rescue me quickly! Notice my telepathy of "love" soon!
SOS 歌：ラプラス・ダークネス
SOS, Sung by: La+ Darknesss
ラプラスが冬優子の曲を異次元カバー
La+ covering Fuyuko's song across dimensions
初めて出逢ったときから ハートが震えてたんだよ
My heart has been trembling ever since we first met.
無意識に意識しちゃう この感じはきっと（重症です）
I find myself conscious of you without thinking. This feeling must be... (serious).
目と目が合うだけで顔が熱いの
My face gets hot just by our eyes meeting.
話しかけられて頭がパニック
My head panics when you talk to me.
ドキドキし過ぎて会話続かない
My heart is pounding too hard to continue the conversation.
My heart beats so fast I can't keep a conversation going
どうすればいいの？ こんな気持ちを
What should I do about these feelings?
（キミとの相性診断） 星占いなら So good So good
(A compatibility test with you) The horoscope says "So good, so good"
（トモダチなんかじゃないよ） ときめいている
(We're not just friends) My heart is fluttering
キミに Fall-in-love 恋の SOS
I'm falling in love with you, a love SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been aching this whole time
ハヤク Rescue 「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Rescue me quickly! Notice my "love" telepathy soon!
これは Fall-in-love 恋の SOS
This is falling in love, a love SOS
もっとキミに近づきたい
I want to get closer to you
終わらせて 片想い My heart
End this unrequited love, my heart
全部抱きしめて
Hold it all close
キミが好きな音楽や 映画のことリサーチして
I research the music and movies you like
SNS見るたびに イイネ押すの （アピールだよ）
Every time I see you on social media, I hit "like" (It's my appeal)
四六時中キミのこと考えて
I think about you 24/7
妄想しながら 枕ギュッとした
I hugged my pillow while daydreaming
明日はどんな服装着ていこうかな
I wonder what clothes I should wear tomorrow
キミ想うだけでなんか照れる
Just thinking of you makes me blush
（キミの名前を呼べば） ただそれだけでも Dreaming Dreaming
(If I call your name) even just that is Dreaming Dreaming
（溺れそうな私を） 助け出して
(I'm about to drown) please rescue me
キミに Fall-in-love 恋の SOS
I'm falling in love with you, a love SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been aching this whole time
ハヤク Rescue 「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Rescue me quickly! Notice my "love" telepathy soon!
これは Fall-in-love 恋の SOS
This is falling in love, a love SOS
もっとキミに近づきたい
I want to get closer to you
終わらせて 片想い My heart
End this unrequited love, my heart
全部抱きしめて
Hold it all close
はーい！
Hi!
というわけで、それぞれの楽曲を交換して歌ってみましたー！
And so, we tried swapping and singing each other's songs!
冬子の「合縁事変」めちゃくちゃかっこよかったぞ！
Fuyuko, "Aien Jihen" was so cool!
この曲のラップ、めっちゃ難しいのに、ちゃんと言えててすごい！さすがアイドルだな。
The rap in this song is super difficult, but you nailed it! Amazing! As expected of an idol.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ラブちゃんの「SOS」、とっても可愛かったよ！
Lab-chan, "SOS" was so cute!
歌ってもらえて嬉しいな。
I'm happy you sang it.
あ、それじゃあ最後に、みんなにもう一曲だけ聴いてもらっちゃおうかな？
Oh, and finally, maybe everyone could listen to just one more song?
この曲大好き！
I love this song!
いつか歌ってみたかったから、冬子と歌えるなんて、めっちゃ嬉しい！
I've always wanted to sing it, so I'm super happy to sing it with Fuyuko!
ふゆ、嬉しい♡
Fuyu is happy too.
ラブちゃんだーいすき♡
I love you, Lab-chan!
うっ…冬子、頑張ってるな…
Ugh... Fuyuko, you're really working hard...
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
Wandering Dream Chaser!
闇を切り刻むように 昂ぶる思い
Emotions rising, as if cutting through the darkness
乱反射 To the stage 見せつけるわ
Diffuse reflection to the stage, I'll show you
目指すものがあるから 心に迷いなんてないの
Because I have something to aim for, there's no hesitation in my heart
どんな試練があっても Going my ray
No matter what trials come, I'm going my way
誰かが作った道を （Dash!）
The path someone else made (Dash!)
追い越したその先で （Breakout!）
After overtaking it (Breakout!)
胸に渡る夢を この手でつかむの
I'll seize the dream that crosses my heart with these hands
胸に　渡る夢を　この手でつかむの
I'll grasp the dream passing through my heart with these hands.
諦めない、絶対
I won't give up, never.
高く高い壁だって　Get Chance & Luck　飛び越え
Even the highest walls, Get Chance & Luck, I'll leap over them.
異彩の光で魅せるわ
I'll enchant you with a brilliant light.
憧れはいつの日か　Grow up & Change　突き抜け
One day, my longing will Grow up & Change, breaking through.
私たちが目指すGoalへ導く(Dance with the shine)
Leading to the Goal we aim for (Dance with the shine).
Day after day　彷徨っても　辿り着く
Day after day, even if I wander, I will arrive.
高鳴る鼓動が鳴り響いてる
My racing heartbeat is echoing.
Wandering Dream Chaser
時代を巻き込むくらい　ほとばしるCrazy
Gushing out Crazy enough to engulf the era.
強引なNaked heart　さらけ出すよ
I'll lay bare my pushy Naked heart.
中途半端じゃなくて　思いのままに暴れたい
Not halfway, I want to go wild as I please.
失うものがあっても　We'll be alright
Even if there's something to lose, We'll be alright.
歪んだ光だって(Bright!)
Even distorted light (Bright!)
重なり研ぎ澄まされ(Be one!)
Overlapping and being sharpened (Be one!)
未来　照らしだせる　チカラになるから
Because it will become the power to illuminate the future.
永く長い道だって　Don't stop & back　駆け抜け
Even on the longest road, Don't stop & back, I'll run through.
新たな世界を拓くよ
I'll open up a new world.
思いを重ねるほど　Heat up & Chain　輝き
The more our feelings overlap, Heat up & Chain, the more we'll shine.
私たちのスピード上げていくから (Step up my heart)
We're going to pick up our speed (Step up my heart).
We just trying　変えていく　変わってく
We just trying, changing it, it's changing.
描いた理想を叶えていく
Fulfilling the ideals we've drawn.
Wandering Dream Chaser
際限の無い厄災にさえ 黄金を踏み散らすのは誰
Who is it that tramples over gold, even in the midst of boundless calamity?
揺れる黒の狂鳴と　禍つ闇のサイレンと
With the swaying black screams, and the sirens of calamity's darkness.
Ruleを聞かないblood エンドバッドさ 暴力 ＂ニンゲン＂をかたる魔獣の声
Blood that doesn't listen to the Rule, it's an end-bad, violent voice of a beast masquerading as a 'human'.
宝ヲ奪ウ者達のcall　焔ト荒ラス者達のgrowl
The call of those who steal treasures, the growl of those who ravage with flames.
Ruleを知らないblood エンドバッドさ 暴力 黄金を踏み散らす奴は誰！
Blood that knows no Rule, it's an end-bad, violence; who is the one trampling over the gold!
終末を嗤う絶望も
Even the despair that laughs at the end.
明日を見据えるReloadも 一喰らう覚悟はあるか？
And the Reload looking towards tomorrow, are you prepared to devour it all?
有るのは虹の夢 或いは紅き翅
There's the rainbow dream, or the crimson wings.
はじめようか
Shall we begin?
the 咆哮！ wo wo wo
The Roar! wo wo wo
燃やしてやろうじゃないか 有象無象 全て
Why don't we burn it all down, every single bit of the rabble.
wo wo wo
研ぎ澄まされた理不尽さえ 呑み込んで
Devouring even the sharpened irrationality.
傷ついたって 壊れたって 護りたい “共火”がある世界！ 上等 サァ
Even if I get hurt, even if I break, I want to protect the world where the 'shared flame' exists! Bring it on, now.
今夜も熱くやろうじゃないか 灼熱ノRed Ruler
Let's do it passionately again tonight, the scorching Red Ruler.
宝ヲ奪ウ者達のcall　焔ト荒ス者達のgrowl
The call of those who steal treasures, the growl of those who ravage with flames
終わりを知らないblood エンドバッドさ　暴力
Blood that knows no end, an end bad... violence
光の裏側で笑う不浄理！
The impurity laughing behind the light!
灯閉ざす雨の音も　静寂に仇なすクロウも
Even the sound of rain closing out the light, even the crow that harms the silence
一刃向かう覚悟はあるか？
Do you have the resolve to face a blade?
ヒトツはヒトの夢　フタツの不確か・生
One is a person's dream, two is uncertain life
はじめようか
Shall we begin?
the 咆哮！
The roar!
WO WO WO
どうかしてやろうじゃないか　有象無象　全て！
Shall we do something about it? All the common rabble!
WO WO WO
導火してやろうじゃないか　奪う者
Shall we ignite the fuse? The thief
WO WO WO
焦がしてやろうじゃないか　有象無象　全て！
Shall we burn it all? All the common rabble!
WO WO WO
その先にある闇さえ　呑み込んで！
Even the darkness beyond, swallow it whole!
傷ついたって　壊れたって
Even if hurt, even if broken
護りたい　“共火”(ともしび)があるんだ　上等 ― サア
There's a "shared flame" I want to protect, bring it on — now
今夜も熱くやろうじゃないか　灼熱ノRedRuler
Let's make it hot tonight too, the red-hot RedRuler
全てのリトルデーモンに捧げる
Dedicated to all Little Demons
堕天の力を！
The power of the Fallen!
Switch
聖なるセカイ夢見てるの？
Are you dreaming of a holy world?
白い翼を背にしたいの？
Do you want white wings on your back?
でも貴方とアナタと私達
But you and you and us
無垢なままではいられない
Can't stay innocent forever
この退屈セカイを渡るには
To traverse this tedious world
力を合わせなきゃ駄目よ
We must join our forces
ほら私と貴方とワタシなら
See, if it's me, you and I
やがて奇跡が起きちゃうって！
A miracle will surely happen!
だけど今は我慢しようか
But for now, let's be patient
伏伏の時 タイミング待ってる
A time of dormancy, waiting for the timing
いつかどこか私と貴方
Someday, somewhere, you and I
出会う筈でしょ unstable world
Are bound to meet, unstable world
異次元フェス開催記念音楽番組
MUSIC BIGBANG!
Other-Dimensional Fest Commemorative Music Program
はぁ～ 皆さんどうでしたか？
Haa~ How was it, everyone?
私たち「ヨハドラ」チームも お互いの曲をカバーさせてもらいました！
Our "Yohadora" team also covered each other's songs!
ドーラ、良かったわ！
Dola, that was great!
とっても新鮮だった！
It was very fresh!
でも あなたの曲も難しかった...
But your song was difficult too...
うう、ありがとうございます！
Uu, thank you very much!
ヨハネの曲が歌えて めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです！
It was so much fun to sing Yohane's song!
そう、ドーラのこの「レッドルーラー」めちゃめちゃ難しいんですけど
Yes, Dola's "Red Ruler" is incredibly difficult, but...
ヨハネ 完璧に歌い上げてて 聴き惚れちゃいました
Yohane sang it perfectly, I was mesmerized
さすがです！
As expected!
ククククッ...
Kukukuku...
でもドーラ
But Dola
この程度で リトルデーモンは満足しないわ
Little Demons won't be satisfied with just this
はい、その通り！
Yes, exactly!
さあ 私たちの歌声に酔いしれなさい！
Now, be intoxicated by our singing voices!
それでは 聴いてください
Now, please listen
ストロベリー・トラッパー！
Strawberry Trapper!
Ready?
待ってないよ... LOVE!!
I'm not waiting... LOVE!!
見つけた！キミは 淋しい瞳だった
Found you! You had lonely eyes
鼓動が鳴ってる「手に入れなさい」と
My heart is beating, saying "Take it"
冷静なほど 熱さを楽しめるの
The cooler you are, the more you can enjoy the heat
高まる想いは 抑えて
Suppress your rising feelings
静かに 集めるキミの情報
Quietly gather information about you
確かに 価値ある Sensitive mind
Surely, a valuable Sensitive mind
背後に歩み寄る スリルがたまらない
The thrill of approaching from behind is irresistible
狙い定めたら 逃がさないから
Once I've aimed, I won't let you get away
逃がさないから My target!!
I won't let you get away, My target!!
(Trap in Dice) 恋の罠から
(Trap in Dice) From the trap of love
(Trap in Night) 始まりたい
(Trap in Night) I want to begin
(Trap in Heart) 踊りながら人生のルーレット
(Trap in Heart) Dancing through the roulette of life
(運命は) ありきたりじゃつまらない
(Fate is) Boring if it's ordinary
特別を感じたいの 奪いたいキミのこと
I want to feel special, I want to steal you away
奪いたいキミのこと
I want to steal you away
待ってないよ... LOVE!!
I'm not waiting... LOVE!!
震える顔が 見たいのなんてさ
Saying I want to see your trembling face...
企むときは きっとワルイ顔ね
When I'm plotting, I'm sure I have a wicked face
いただきたいのは...その心よ
What I want to take... is your heart
脆くて危うい 優しさ
Fragile and precarious kindness
静かな孤独を愛するキミ
You who love quiet solitude
確かな 輝き放つの
Radiating a certain brilliance
気づかれないうちに 私のモノにしたい
I want to make you mine before you notice
狙い定めたよ 逃がさないから
I've aimed, I won't let you get away
逃がさないから My target!!
I won't let you get away, My target!!
(Trick in Dice) 恋に賭けたら
(Trick in Dice) If you bet on love
(Trick in Night) 後に引けない
(Trick in Night) There's no turning back
(Trick in Heart) 勝つだけでしょ人生はルーレット
(Trick in Heart) You just have to win, life is a roulette
(運命と) わかる出会い素敵だわ
(As fate) A meeting that reveals itself is wonderful
特別を感じたら
If you feel something special
ドーラ、召喚！
Dola, summon!
「手に入れて」秘めたる声はberryの香り Trap in one night
"Take it" the hidden voice smells like berry, Trap in one night
赤いberry 甘く強く... 滴って
Red berry, sweet and strong... dripping
(Trick in Dice)
恋に賭けたら
If you bet on love
(Trick in Night)
後に引けない
There's no turning back
(Trick in Heart)
勝つだけでしょ
You just have to win
人生はルーレット
Life is a roulette
(Trap in Dice)
恋の罠から
From the trap of love
(Trap in Night)
始まりたい
I want to begin
(Trap in Heart)
踊りながら
While dancing
人生のルーレット
The roulette of life
(運命は)
(Fate is)
ありきたりじゃつまらない
Boring if it's ordinary
特別を感じたいの
I want to feel something special
奪いたいキミのこと
I want to steal you away
待ってないよ
I won't wait
甘い甘い berry
Sweet, sweet berry
心に赤の誘惑
A red temptation in my heart
Berry Trapper
狙い定めたよ
I've set my sights on you
というわけで、ふゆたちのコラボ歌唱を聞いてもらったんですが、
So, we've just heard Fuyu and the others' collaboration performance,
みんなはどうだった？
how was it everyone?
最高だったわ！
It was the best!
本当に一緒に歌えたんだな。
We really got to sing together.
あぁ、夢みたい。
Ah, it's like a dream.
まだ現実とは思えない。
I still can't believe it's real.
うーん。
Hmm.
なんだかまだリトルデーモンたちが満足していないようね。
It seems my Little Demons aren't quite satisfied yet.
仕方ないわね。
I guess it can't be helped.
特別にもっとこの世を揺るがす
I'll show you an even more world-shaking,
異次元なコラボを魅せてあげる。
interdimensional collaboration, just for you.
みんなで練習してきたもんな。
We all practiced together for this, after all.
そうそう。
Right, right.
もっと虜にしちゃいます。
We're going to captivate you even more.
みんな、準備はいい？
Everyone, are you ready?
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
異次元★BIGBANG！
Ijigen ★ BIGBANG!
Wow wow wow 目指す場所まで
Wow wow wow to the place we aim for
Wow wow wow 一緒に見に行こう
Wow wow wow let's go see it together
L!O!L! L!O!L!
L!O!L!O!L!O!L!O!L!
Yes! 最高の巡り合いだね
Yes! It's the best encounter
交わるはずのない Heart & Voice
Heart & Voice that were never meant to cross
夢と声と夢が重なってく
Dreams, voices, and dreams are overlapping
この瞬間 (oh yes!)
At this moment (oh yes!)
断然胸が熱くなるよ
My heart is definitely getting fired up
超絶怒涛 Show-time へおいで
Come to the transcendentally stormy Show-time
愛と I LOVE アイが
Love and I LOVE Ai
ここにあって きみがいる
Are here, and you are here
叶わないこと なんてないから
Because there's nothing that can't come true
叶えにいこう ぎゅっと
Let's go make it come true, tightly
手を握ったら 勇気みなぎる
If we grip hands, courage overflows
美しく咲く花のように
Like flowers blooming beautifully
僕らの言葉が舞い
Our words flutter
照らし出していく
Shining out
優しく強くこの歌で
Gently and strongly with this song
この世界中 包み込んで
Wrapping around the whole world
離さないよ 約束するからさ
I won't let go, I promise
ついてきて！
So follow me!
幾千の星から
From thousands of stars
光が集まって
The light gathers
ひとつになって みんなの色
Becoming one, everyone's colors
あわせたら Beautiful!
When combined, it's beautiful!
ずっと消えないで 未来まで
Don't ever fade away, until the future
永遠に続くメロディアス
An eternal melodious tune
もっと（もっと）遠く
Further (and further)
飛べる気がするんだよ to you
I feel like I can fly to you
Wow wow wow 目指す場所まで
Wow wow wow to the place we aim for
（知りたい？）
(Want to know?)
Wow wow wow 一緒に見に行こう
Wow wow wow let's go see it together
感動的な旅にしようよ
Let's make it an emotional journey
人生はまさに Kiss & Cry
Life is exactly Kiss & Cry
明日今日も 何が起こるなんてサプライズ
What happens today and tomorrow is a surprise
嬉しいことも 楽しいことも
Both happy things and fun things
全部あげたい うんと
I want to give them all to you, plenty
手を伸ばしたら 誰かに届く
If you reach out, it will reach someone
刻んでく 歴史の上に
Carving it into history
僕らは歩いてきた
We have walked along
可能性ってさ 有限じゃない
Possibilities aren't finite
無限大だ（∞だ）
They're infinite (∞)
インフィニティ
Infinity
塗り替えてく 新しいページ
We're rewriting a new page
まだまだ止まらない ついてきて！！
We're still not stopping, follow us!!
まだまだ止まらない ついてきて!!
Still not stopping, keep up!!
異次元のチカラで ドキドキ高まって
With the power of another dimension, my heart's pounding increases
どこまでだって いけるかもって
Thinking I might be able to go anywhere
溢れ出した Curious! ずっと忘れない 未来まで
Overflowing Curious! I won't forget, until the future
この景色はメモリアル 一瞬（一秒）だって
This scenery is a memorial, even just for a second
宝物みたいだよ-- for me
It's like a treasure-- for me
ラララララ...
La la la la la...
大切にしよう
Let's treasure it
愛をこめて歌おう
Let's sing with love
どんどん大きくなってゆく輪
A circle that keeps growing bigger
踊る踊る 新しい風
Dancing, dancing, a new breeze
ねえこんなはじめての予感
Hey, this first-time premonition
奇跡みたい...!
It's like a miracle...!
L! O! L! L! O! L! L! O! L!
幾億の星から 光が集まって
Light gathering from hundreds of millions of stars
ひとつになって みんなの色
Becoming one, everyone's colors
あわせたら超 Beautiful!!! ずっと消えないで 未来まで
When combined, it's super Beautiful!!! Please don't ever fade, until the future
永遠に続くメロディアス もっと（もっと）遠く
An eternal melodious, further (and further)
飛べる気がするんだよ-- to you
I feel like I can fly-- to you
Wow wow 大好きだって叫びたい
Wow wow, I want to shout that I love you
きみときみときみに伝えたい
I want to tell you, you, and you
眩しい眩しい目指す場所まで
To the bright, bright place we're aiming for
一緒に見に行こう
Let's go see it together
Wow wow 一緒に見に行こう
Wow wow, let's go see it together
異次元フェス開催記念音楽番組 MUSIC BIGBANG!
Another Dimension Fes Celebration Music Program: MUSIC BIGBANG!
どう？異次元フェスのために作られた楽曲
How was it? The song created for Another Dimension Fes
「異次元★♥BIGBANG」を披露させていただいたわ。
“Ijigen Big Bang,” which we just performed.
この曲で一つになれた感じがしたね。
I felt like we became one through this song.
...ありがとうございます。
...Thank you very much.
いや、この舞台で、この4人で歌えるなんて
Wow, being able to sing on a stage like this with these four...
最後泣きそうだった...
I was about to cry at the end...
冬優子たちにとっても、見てくれてるみんなにとっても
For us, and for everyone watching...
貴重な時間になったんじゃないかなって思います。
...I think it's been a precious time.
ね？
Right?
そうね。
That's right.
でもこれは前夜祭みたいなもの。
But this is like an eve-of-festival.
本番は明日よ！
The real thing is tomorrow!
私たちを含め、たくさんのアイドルが
A live concert where many idols, including us,
切磋琢磨するライブが、ついに開催されるのだから！
will work hard together is finally being held!
とっても楽しみだね。
It's so exciting.
みんなふゆの虜にしちゃいます。
I'll make everyone fall for Fuyu.
望むところよ！
That's what I'm talking about!
ラプちゃんもドーラちゃんも明日からのイベント、応援してくれるんだよね？
La-chan and Dola-chan, you'll be supporting the event starting tomorrow, right?
意気込みなんて聞いちゃってもいいかな？
Can I hear your enthusiasm?
アンバサダーとして頑張ってきたけど、ついに本番だ！
I've worked hard as an ambassador, and it's finally the real thing!
もうただのオタクとして楽しむぞ！
I'm going to enjoy it just as an otaku now!
プロデューサーも一緒に盛り上がろう！
Producers, let's get hyped together!
アンバサダーのお話をいただいてからあっという間に、ライブもう明日！
Since I was asked to be an ambassador, it's already time for the concert tomorrow!
まだちょっと心がソワソワしていますが
My heart is still a bit restless, but...
スクールアイドルを応援する皆さん！
To everyone supporting school idols!
声出しの準備はできていますか！もう明日ですよ！
Are you ready to shout? It's tomorrow!
一緒に楽しみましょう！
Let's enjoy it together!
ああ、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you.
明日からもよろしくね。
Looking forward to working with you from tomorrow too.
というわけで、そろそろ番組も終わりなんだけど
And so, the program is almost over...
最後に明日のライブの告知を、アンバサダーの二人からお願いするわね。
But first, I'll ask the two ambassadors to announce tomorrow's concert.
はい！
Yes!
異次元フェス アイドルマスター★♥ラブライブ！歌合戦 in 東京ドーム
Another Dimension Fes: Idolm@ster ★♥ Love Live! Utagassen in Tokyo Dome
DAY1 あす12月9日(土) 開演 17:00
DAY1: Tomorrow, Dec 9 (Sat), Starts 17:00
場所は東京ドーム。
The venue is Tokyo Dome.
総勢100名以上のアイドルとメンバーたちのパフォーマンス
Performances by over 100 idols and members...
絶対に見逃せません。
...you absolutely cannot miss it.
みんな、準備は万端？
Is everyone fully prepared?
忘れ物はない？
Did you forget anything?
Tシャツよし、マフラータオルよし、チケットよし。
T-shirt, check. Muffler towel, check. Ticket, check.
買いそびれちゃったグッズは、会場物販もあるからぜひぜひチェックしてください。
If there's merch you missed, there's also venue sales, so please check it out.
アイドルマスター・ラブライブ！ブレード
Idolm@ster/Love Live! Blade...
ドーラも買いました。
Dola also bought one.
明日明日、目一杯特別な時間を楽しみましょう。
Let's enjoy a truly special time tomorrow and the day after.
じゃ、観客席で会おうな。
Well, see you in the audience.
隣にいるかもよ。
I might be right next to you.
そして、ASOBI STAGEさんとABEMAさんで配信されるから
And, it'll be streamed on ASOBI STAGE and ABEMA...
現地の人も配信で見てる人も一緒に見ような。
...so let's all watch together, whether you're there in person or online.
めちゃくちゃたくさん曲やるらしいから
I heard they're going to perform a ton of songs...
楽しみだ！
I'm looking forward to it!
終わったらアーカイブでも見返せるから、絶対何回も見るぞ！
Since we can rewatch it in the archives after, I'll definitely watch it many times!
今日、この番組を見てちょっとでもいいなって思ってもらえたら、
If watching this program today made you think even a little bit that it was good,
配信で、絶対絶対見てほしいな。
I really, really want you to watch the stream.
冬優、待ってますね。
Fuyu will be waiting.
そうね。
That's right.
絶対に後悔させないライブを披露して、会場すべてを...
We'll put on a performance you won't regret, and the entire venue...
いえ、全世界を魅了してみせるわ。
...no, we'll captivate the whole world.
じゃあ最後に、今日の感想をひとことずつ。
Then finally, a quick word from everyone on their thoughts for today.
まずは冬優から。
First, from Fuyu.
今日はグループやユニットの壁を越えて、
Today, crossing the barriers of groups and units,
歌で繋がれた感じがして、とっても楽しかったです。
I felt we were connected through song, and it was so much fun.
今日番組を見てくれたみんなも、そう思ってもらえてると、冬優嬉しいです。
If everyone who watched the program today feels the same way, Fuyu would be happy.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
じゃあ次は、ラプちゃん。
Next up, Lap-chan.
はい！今日は最後まで観てくれて本当にありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much for watching until the end today!
ただの一般プロデューサーだったのに、気づいたらここにいました...
I was just an ordinary Producer, but before I knew it, I was here...
本当に本当に嬉しいし、
I'm really, really happy,
今日は正直緊張しました！
and to be honest, I was nervous today!
自我を保てないかと思いました...
I thought I wouldn't be able to keep my sense of self...
大好きな冬優子と、
Being able to sing with my favorite Fuyuko
大好きなアイマスの楽曲を歌えて、本当に嬉しかったぞ！
and my favorite Idolmaster songs, I was really happy!
ありがとうございます。本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you. Thank you so much.
これからもVTuberというよりかは、プロデューサーが本職なので、精進していきたいと思います。
From now on, rather than being a VTuber, my main job is a Producer, so I'll keep working hard.
ごめんなさい！うちの社長ー！
I'm sorry! To my agency's CEO!
じゃあ次、ドーラ。
Next, Dora.
改めまして、ラブライブ！アンバサダーを務めさせていただきましたドーラです！
Once again, I'm Dora, and I've been serving as the Love Live! Ambassador!
いや本当に、これが前夜祭なのか!?というくらい、めちゃめちゃ楽しかったです。
Wow, really, it was so much fun that I wondered if this was really just the pre-festival!?
今日こんなに楽しかったら、明日はどうなっちゃうの？
If it's this much fun today, what's going to happen tomorrow?
と、怯えてます。
I'm almost scared.
本当にラブライブ！のこと、そしてスクールアイドルのみんなのことを好きでいてよかったなと思いました。
I really felt glad that I love Love Live! and all the school idols.
みんなが知っていて、ドレイクが知らないラブライブ！の魅力も、きっとまだまだあると思います。
I'm sure there are still many charms of Love Live! that everyone knows but Dora doesn't.
なので、もっともっと応援して、もっともっと大好きになっていけたらなと思っております。
So, I hope to support them more and more, and fall in love with them even more.
こんな素敵な機会をくださって、本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for giving me such a wonderful opportunity!
冬優子ちゃんと、ラプ様、
Fuyuko-chan, Lap-sama,
そして、ヨハネと歌えたこと、誇りに生きていきます。
and being able to sing with Yohane, I will live with pride.
これでヨハネの魅力もみんなに伝わって、
With this, Yohane's charm has been conveyed to everyone,
今頃、堕天しまくりなはず！
and by now, everyone should be falling from grace like crazy!
クククッ...
Hehehe...
全国の全ての人間が、闇の力にひれ伏し、
All humans across the country will bow down to the power of darkness,
堕天する姿があらわれて、
and as they fall from grace,
このヨハネも気分がいいわ。
even I, Yohane, feel good.
明日もまた会場をリトルデーモンたちで埋め尽くして、
Tomorrow, we'll fill the venue with Little Demons again,
このヨハネ様の歌声にひれ伏すことは、
and bowing down to this Yohane-sama's singing voice
定められた運命（ディスティニー）。
is our predetermined destiny.
それじゃあ、名残惜しいけど今日はこれでおしまい。
Well then, it's a shame, but that's all for today.
明日、約束の地、東京ドームで会いましょう！
Let's meet tomorrow at the promised land, Tokyo Dome!
それでは！せーの！
Now then! One, two!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!